Guide to the Abraham Robinson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1939-1988; Series I; 5.25' (13 boxes)
  - Writings not on the published bibliography
    - Linear Geometry in Rings with Zero Divisors, Circa 1950 (Box 11, Folder 166)
    - On the Foundations of Dimensional Analysis, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 167)
    - On Rational Tests in Algebra, 1951-1957 (Box 11, Folder 168)
    - Colloquium on the Foundations of Mathematics, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 169)
    - Book reviews, Circa 1956-1969 (Box 11, Folder 170)
    - On the Transformation of Convex Point Sets, 1957-1962 (Box 11, Folder 171)
    - On the Independence of the Axioms of Definiteness, 1957-1962 (Box 11, Folder 172)
    - Lectures on Differential Algebra, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 173)
    - Mathematical Logic and Mechanical Mathematics I, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Mathematical Logic and Mechanical Mathematics II, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Forcing by finitely generated structures, Circa 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Non-standard analysis — transparencies for a presentation, Circa 1971 (Box 11, Folder 177a)
    - Abraham Robinson's Notes on a Relatively Effective Procedure Getting all Quasi-integer Solutions of Diophantine Equations with Positive Genus, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 177b)
    - Topicos da Teoria Dos Modelos, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 178)
    - Mathematical Thought, undated (Box 12, Folder 179)
    - "Mathematical Method: A Lecture on the Solution of Mathematical Problems in General", undated (Box 12, Folder 180)
    - Logic as the Science of Mathematical Reasoning, undated (Box 12, Folder 181)
    - Metamathematical Logic - Lattice Theory, undated (Box 12, Folder 182)
    - "Open Sets and Closed Curves" for Open Set Scientific Society, undated (Box 12, Folder 183)
    - Beweis des Grossen Fermatschen Satzes für Alle Potewzen 4 in (u gauazalig), undated (Box 12, Folder 184)
    - Extension Theory of Commutative Fields, undated (Box 12, Folder 185)
    - Model theory - transparency, undated (Box 12, Folder 186)
    - On Hilbert's Irreducibility Theorem, undated (Box 12, Folder 187)
    - On Integral Relations for Lané functions, undated (Box 12, Folder 188)
    - Solution of Ritt's Decomposition Problem, undated (Box 12, Folder 189)
    - Vollständigkeits in der Metamathematick der Algebra, undated (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - Fragments, undated (Box 12, Folder 191)
    - Course material
      - College of Aeronautics: lecture notes on mathematics, Circa 1950 (Box 12, Folder 192)
      - University of Toronto: lecture notes on wave propagation, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 193)
      - University of Toronto: annual examinations, 1951-1957 (Box 12, Folder 194)
      - College of Aeronautics: lecture notes on stochastic processes, Circa 1950 (Box 12, Folder 195)
      - University of California, Los Angeles, 1961,1963 (Box 13, Folder 196)
      - Yale University: lecture notes on set theory, 1968-1973 (Box 13, Folder 197)
      - Yale University, 1969-1970,1973 (Box 13, Folder 198)
      - Yale University: notes on logic [model theory], Math 160a and 160b; student notes on course by Gregory Charlin, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 199)
      - Yale University: lecture notes on model theory, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 200)
    - Lecture notes on mathematical logic, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 201)
- Correspondence and Other Papers by and about Abraham Robinson, 1918-1985; Series II; 1.5' (4 boxes)
  The series is arranged in alphabetical order by record type.
  - Correspondence of Abraham Robinson
    - A (Box 14, Folder 202)
    - American Mathematical Monthly
      General
      See: box 15, folder 232
    - Anderson, Alan Ross
      See: box 14, folders 203-204
    - Association for Symbolic Logic, 1967-1974 (Box 14, Folder 203-204)
    - B (Box 14, Folder 205)
    - Benacerraf, Paul
    - Bucknell University, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 206)
    - C (Box 14, Folder 207)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1960-1971 (Box 14, Folder 208)
    - Church, Alonzo
    - Craig, William
    - Curry, Haskell B., 1952-1970 (Box 14, Folder 209)
    - D (Box 14, Folder 210)
    - Dictionary of Scientific Biography, 1966-1975 (Box 14, Folder 211)
    - Dreben, B. S.
    - E (Box 14, Folder 212)
    - F (Box 14, Folder 213)
    - Fenstad, Jens E.
    - G (Box 14, Folder 214)
    - Gauthier-Villars, Éditeur, 1966-1973, undated (Box 14, Folder 215)
    - Gödel, Kurt, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 216)
    - Goodwin, Roberta
    - H (Box 14, Folder 217)
    - Hájek, Petr
    - Halpern, James D.
    - Henkin, Leon
    - Heyting, A., 1955-1973 (Box 14, Folder 218)
    - Holden-Day Inc., 1963-1975 (Box 14, Folder 219)
    - I (Box 14, Folder 220)
    - J (Box 14, Folder 221)
    - Jacobsen, Norman
      See: box 15, folder 245
    - Journal of Mathematical Physics, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 222)
    - K (Box 14, Folder 223)
    - Karlin, Samuel
      See: box 15, folder 244
    - Keisler, H. Jerome, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 224)
    - Kelemen, Peter, 1969-1970, undated (Box 14, Folder 225)
    - Körner, Stephan, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 226)
    - Kreisel, Georg, 1956-1974 (Box 14, Folder 227)
    - L (Box 14, Folder 228)
    - Levy, Azriel
    - Lightstone, A. Harold, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 229)
    - Luxemburg, W. A. J., 1962-1974 (Box 14, Folder 230)
    - M (Box 15, Folder 231)
    - Mathematical Association of America, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 232)
    - Müller, Gert, 1967-1974 (Box 15, Folder 233)
    - N (Box 15, Folder 234)
    - North-Holland Publishing Company, 1951-1972 (Box 15, Folder 235)
    - North-Holland Publishing Company, 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 236)
    - O (Box 15, Folder 237)
    - P-Q (Box 15, Folder 238)
    - Parsons, Charles D.
    - Prior, A. N.
    - Quine, W. Van
    - R (Box 15, Folder 239)
    - Rogers, Hartley
    - Roquette, Peter, 1965-1974 (Box 15, Folder 240)
    - S (Box 15, Folder 241)
    - Sacks, Gerald E.
    - Scott, Dana
    - Shoenfield, Joseph R.
    - T-U-V (Box 15, Folder 242)
    - University of Toronto, 1951-1961, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 243)
    - W-X-Y-Z (Box 15, Folder 244)
    - Yale University, 1965-1973 (Box 15, Folder 245)
    - Unidentified correspondence (Box 15, Folder 246)
    - Recommendations: A-J (Box 15, Folder 247)
    - Recommendations: K-Z (Box 15, Folder 248)
  - Correspondence of Mrs. Abraham Robinson with Peter Roquette, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 249)
  - Curricula vitae and reports concerning Abraham Robinson's work, 1956-1961 (Box 16, Folder 250)
  - Diaries of Abraham Robinson, 1931-1933, 1940, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 251-252)
  - Family memorabilia, 1918, 1927, undated (Box 16, Folder 253)
  - Honors and awards to Abraham Robinson, 1942-1972 (Box 16, Folder 254)
    See also: folio
  - Interviews and other material from the Robinson Memorial Conference at Yale, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 255)
  - Letters of condolence to Mrs. Abraham Robinson: A-H, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 256)
  - Letters of condolence to Mrs. Abraham Robinson: I-Z, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 257)
  - List of Abraham Robinson's Ph.D students, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 258)
  - Notecards concerning mathematical bibliography by Abraham Robinson: A-M, undated (Box 16, Folder 259)
  - Notecards concerning mathematical bibliography by Abraham Robinson: M-Z, undated (Box 16, Folder 260)
  - Photograph, undated (Box 16, Folder 261)
  - Programs and announcements for Abraham Robinson lectures, 1947-1973 (Box 16, Folder 262)
  - Program and remarks at memorial service, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 263)
  - Published material referring to Abraham Robinson or his works, 1950-1972 (Box 17, Folder 264)
  - Published material referring to Abraham Robinson or his works, 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 264a)
  - Published material referring to Abraham Robinson or his works, 1975-1985, undated (Box 17, Folder 265)
  - Reminiscences of Abraham Robinson by colleagues: A-S, 1976-1979 (Box 17, Folder 266)
  - Reminiscences of Abraham Robinson by colleagues: T-Z, 1975-1977 (Box 17, Folder 267)
  - Reviews of books by Abraham Robinson, 1953-1980 (Box 17, Folder 268)
  - Student notes and memorabilia of Abraham Robinson, 1928-1936, undated (Box 17, Folder 269)
  - Student notes and wartime memorabilia of Abraham Robinson, 1940-1945 (Box 17, Folder 270)
  - Transcription of remarks and other material from the ceremony dedicating the chair in memory of Abraham Robinson at the Hebrew University, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 271)
    See also: box 18, folder 274
  - Travel papers, 1946-1970 (Box 17, Folder 271a)
  - Oversize from folder 254, 1936-1974 (Box 18, Folder 272)
    Folio
  - Oversize from folder 262, 1966, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 273)
  - Oversize from folder 271, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 274)
  - Yale University Conference on Model Theory, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 275)